<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Series on Dave Blogs About Stuff</title><link>https://daveblogs.me/categories/series/</link><description>Recent content in Series on Dave Blogs About Stuff</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 05 Jan 2025 10:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://daveblogs.me/categories/series/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Star Trek: Deep Space Nine Season 1</title><link>https://daveblogs.me/p/star-trek-deep-space-nine-s01/</link><pubDate>Sun, 05 Jan 2025 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://daveblogs.me/p/star-trek-deep-space-nine-s01/</guid><description>&lt;img src="https://walter-r2.trakt.tv/images/shows/000/000/579/posters/thumb/660c7672b2.jpg" alt="Featured image of post Star Trek: Deep Space Nine Season 1" />&lt;p>Deep Space Nine is very much just more Star Trek with a lot of the same things to love and the same drags. Getting the negative out of the way first, most episodes do not need the full hour time slot. Many episodes would feel more effective in a half hour time slot, and the show feels stretched to fill out the full hour. There is no better example of this padding than the intro sequence. It feels so long and all we get is a rotating image of Deep Space Nine.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Given the stationary setting of Deep Space Nine, the show mostly focuses on particular types of stories with the social and political dynamics of the Bajoran and Federation relationship and trade through the wormhole. There are a few away mission style missions mixed in as well, but we spend most of our time on Deep Space Nine. This mostly just shifts the format from the Enterprise going somewhere, to stuff coming to Deep Space Nine. The cast of characters is mostly good, Odo and Dax are standouts and both unique and very interesting characters with evolving backgrounds. Kira, Sisko, and Quark are all fairly standard characters that work well with the types of stories the show wants to tell (and of course it is nice to see O&amp;rsquo;Brien again). My least favorite character is Dr. Bashir, who is often annoying and not nearly as interesting as past doctors.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>There are some standout episodes in the first season. &amp;ldquo;Dax&amp;rdquo; has a classic trial style episode that examines justice and existence in the context of a multi-lifespan species. &amp;ldquo;Progress&amp;rdquo; examines those left behind by industrialization. &amp;ldquo;If Wishes Were Horses&amp;rdquo; is a strange but delightful one where characters thoughts manifest and create a whole bunch of conflicts around the station. There are a bunch of episodes reflecting on religion, mostly focused on Bajoran and Federation dynamics that are mostly strong, including &amp;ldquo;In the Hands of the Prophets&amp;rdquo; as the standout. On the other hand, we do get an annoying Q episode with &amp;ldquo;Q-Less&amp;rdquo;, which is kinda as annoying as other Q episodes from past series. And it would not be Star Trek without some episodes that toe the lines into nonsense like &amp;ldquo;Move Along Home&amp;rdquo; with the board game made real. All in all I am looking forward to more Star Trek Deep Space Nine and working through the rest of the series.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Ghost in the Shell: Arise - Alternative Architecture</title><link>https://daveblogs.me/p/ghost-in-the-shell-arise-alternative/</link><pubDate>Sat, 07 Dec 2024 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://daveblogs.me/p/ghost-in-the-shell-arise-alternative/</guid><description>&lt;img src="https://cdn.myanimelist.net/images/anime/5/72037.jpg" alt="Featured image of post Ghost in the Shell: Arise - Alternative Architecture" />&lt;p>Getting back to Ghost in the Shell after taking a break is an immediate reminder to how interesting the psychological and philosophical questions that lie at the core of the world building. While the original movie still stands the test of time, I have enjoyed the increased time to bake the tv series are privy to. Arise is an interesting case as well, as it is a new origin story, and most characters are pretty darn similar, except for Mokoto&amp;rsquo;s appearance (which I thought would be explained, and maybe I missed it&amp;hellip;).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>My main criticism of Arise is that of the five movies in the tv serialized version of it (Alternative Architecture), there is just a bit of unevenness. None are particularly bad, but some of them feel rushed and one or two feel stretched. Seeing Mokoto and Batou start on opposite sides was different and gave some more depth to their relationship. The same is true for a few of the other characters, but Batou definitely got the most screentime of the rest of the crew. More Logicoma is always a good thing as well.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The Fire-Starter virus was always interesting in the original movie, but it felt like the movie had to juggle Mokoto&amp;rsquo;s inner struggle and the impact of the virus, and the result was a bit less time to see just how impactful the virus could be. The five episodes in Arise gives us different stories about how the virus is being used and the difficulty of combatting it. I think at the end of the day it is probably not as strong as some other series in the canon (like SAC), but I am a sucker for Production I.G and deeper and more pensive dives into philosophical questions, and Arise is both of those things.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>