<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Book on Dave Blogs About Stuff</title><link>https://daveblogs.me/categories/book/</link><description>Recent content in Book on Dave Blogs About Stuff</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 30 Dec 2024 17:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://daveblogs.me/categories/book/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>The Rosie Project by Graeme Simsion</title><link>https://daveblogs.me/p/rosie-project/</link><pubDate>Mon, 30 Dec 2024 17:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://daveblogs.me/p/rosie-project/</guid><description>&lt;img src="https://images-na.ssl-images-amazon.com/images/S/compressed.photo.goodreads.com/books/1371651741i/16181775.jpg" alt="Featured image of post The Rosie Project by Graeme Simsion" />&lt;p>I was shocking charmed by this book from the get-go. Media that centers around socially challenged folks (like Asperger syndrome in this case) can feel very trite and making humor of the situation very quickly feels like punching down. This book largely avoids a lot of those pitfalls and finds humor in the social awkwardness that feels directed towards encouraging Don or humor from his perspective. It also helps that all of his friends have very genuine relationships with him and work with him in positive and encouraging ways.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The book largely follows the traditional rom-com format, with a bumpy road for our couple and a mystery background plot. Rosie is introduced fairly early on and is a very charming character with her own quirks and preferences. Most of the other candidates for the Wife Project lead to comedic moments, especially the sole passing candidate Bianca. The dancing scene is among the best moments of the book, one that reminds us that Don has a bunch of empathy and prevents Don from becoming too saccharine. The other great scene, the bartending scene, is also excellent and gives us a moment to really celebrate Don&amp;rsquo;s capabilities.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Maybe the only criticism I have of the book is that is comes close to treating Asperger syndrome like a superpower at times. I think the picking up dancing and bartending parts are where this is the most prevalent. It is hard to criticize it too much since the scenes payoff so well. The trip to New York for Don and Rosie is excellent and we get to learn a bit more about Rosie and Don in ways that make us appreciate them each more and really root for them. The ending of the trip maybe feels a bit too arbitrary and just sticking to the format of needing more drama leading into the final arc. It does allow the ending to shine and sets up some good eureka moments for Don culminating in their HEA. I am very interested in where Simsion takes the couple in the second part of the story and am looking forward to reading it.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Trust by Hernan Diaz</title><link>https://daveblogs.me/p/trust-hernan-diaz/</link><pubDate>Mon, 09 Dec 2024 15:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://daveblogs.me/p/trust-hernan-diaz/</guid><description>&lt;img src="https://images-na.ssl-images-amazon.com/images/S/compressed.photo.goodreads.com/books/1631246461i/58210933.jpg" alt="Featured image of post Trust by Hernan Diaz" />&lt;p>For about the first half of this book it is not really clear where we are going, which did make it a little less &amp;ldquo;sticky&amp;rdquo; off the line. The Rask story as a standalone is not particularly special and its connect with the autobiographical draft is not immediately clear. Thankfully, the stage-setting does not wear out its welcome and when Ida&amp;rsquo;s perspective introduces the connection it feels like an earned twist. It quickly becomes a complex detective game with a satisfying reveal at the end.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Part of what makes the novel so successful is how reasonable it would be to believe any single account of the historical story of Andrew and Mildred Bevel. Each story successfully justifies its perspective on these characters. It is also interesting how all the stories are about capital and the wielding of capital. The Rask story is about a tycoon who wields wealth to make more wealth, even at substantial cost to the stability of the market. The autobiography is about Andrew applying wealth to impose his will on the world, erase public perceptions of his life that are not to his liking and fill in the gap with his own narrative. Ida&amp;rsquo;s memoir is about a being exposed to the world of wealth from the outside and juxtapositioning it against an anarchist anti-capitalist upbringing. Finally Mildred&amp;rsquo;s diary communicates her struggle with being the mastermind behind the plan, but due to her gender, being unable to be the face of the plan due to societal gender roles and norms.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The point being made here about wealth having an strong force over narrative and perception is not novel on its own, but what makes it work here is the tightness of the story telling and the tiny bits and pieces we are encouraged to reflect back on after being presented with new evidence and perspectives. The theme of trust at the center of the novel is as important as ever to reflect on. It shows how public perspective and narrative can be bought and the danger of trusting those stories without critical analysis. It is also not the last of an infinite series of self-important capitalist mongrels messing up the world for the rest of us while pitching themselves as the hero.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>With a Little Luck by Marissa Meyer</title><link>https://daveblogs.me/p/with-a-little-luck-marissa-meyer/</link><pubDate>Wed, 27 Nov 2024 17:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://daveblogs.me/p/with-a-little-luck-marissa-meyer/</guid><description>&lt;img src="https://images-na.ssl-images-amazon.com/images/S/compressed.photo.goodreads.com/books/1686948017i/63291997.jpg" alt="Featured image of post With a Little Luck by Marissa Meyer" />&lt;p>I have mostly enjoyed everything by Marissa Meyer after getting pulled into The Lunar Chronicles series. I do not think anything has been quite as good as that series, but still very enjoyable. Something about her particular style of magical realism/fairytale magic is very charming and makes for fun reads. The only book that did not quite grab me was Instant Karma, which was probably amongst the least &amp;ldquo;magical&amp;rdquo; of her novels. Still a fun read, but not one I think about often. When I heard we were heading back to Fortuna Beach for a round two, I was happy to see a bit more of these characters, but also a bit hesitant since this world was not my among my favorites from Meyer.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I am always happy to be proven wrong. While I would admit that this book at times feels downright pandering to a nerd audience, it is effective in how it breaks down the traditional nerd and popular kids social circles. It definitely makes me wish that traditional nerdy hobbies had crossed over more into the mainstream when I was in my high school years. There is without a doubt as portion of my enjoyment of this story that is derived from this wish-fulfillment, but the particular way it reflects on social circles and perceptions is where it prevents it from feeling trite. One memorable example is where nerd Jude and popular girl crush Maya are discussing social life and Maya explains that social circles can feel like boxes, that she felt limited by the expectations of others on those in the popular girl clique. It refined a somewhat unbelievable quirk of Maya being very interesting and adept at D&amp;amp;D into something that allows for a more empathetic and relatable perspective on Maya. Moments like these (and there are a few) were a refinement of story arcs that did not quite hit the mark in Instant Karma.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>That is not to say this is a perfect story. The pure luck related to the magic d20 went a bit too far and felt contrite. The thirty-plus heads coin flips was too much for example, and on the flip side the bad luck felt too punishing. There were a subset of perceived good luck occurrences (like Jude developing a friendship with Maya) and perceived bad luck occurrences that felt like they were derived from confidence (or lack of), but the over the top ones blurred the lines a bit too much. It felt the most successful when it hit that magical realism sweet-spot. It was also great to see some more of Prudence and Quint and how they are living out their HEA in their own quirky way.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>While not perfect and a bit too campy at times, I was really delighted by With a Little Luck, and found myself flying through the back half with a lot of glee.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>