<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Fantastic Beasts on Dave Blogs About Stuff</title><link>https://daveblogs.me/tags/fantastic-beasts/</link><description>Recent content in Fantastic Beasts on Dave Blogs About Stuff</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 29 Nov 2024 09:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://daveblogs.me/tags/fantastic-beasts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Fantastic Beasts: The Secrets of Dumbledore</title><link>https://daveblogs.me/p/fantastic-beasts-the-secrets-of-dumbledore/</link><pubDate>Fri, 29 Nov 2024 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://daveblogs.me/p/fantastic-beasts-the-secrets-of-dumbledore/</guid><description>&lt;img src="https://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/en/3/34/Fantastic_Beasts-_The_Secrets_of_Dumbledore.png" alt="Featured image of post Fantastic Beasts: The Secrets of Dumbledore" />&lt;p>The &amp;ldquo;let&amp;rsquo;s just make this single movie a trilogy&amp;rdquo; strikes again. While not quite as bad as the Crimes of Grindlewald, this movie falls flat for many similar reasons, mainly that it feels way too long for the amount of plot the movie conveys. Most scenes feel either too long or unnecessary and the cumulative effect by the end of the movie is tiring. There are a few charming and funny scenes (the dumb crab walk in the prison for example), but it all feels irrelevant to the main plot.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The climax scene of the movie is also a great example of the sloppy storytelling found throughout the movie. All of a sudden we switch from what seems like an election, to just letting the Qilin choose the next leader and everyone is just going along with it? Not to mention earlier in the movie we are told that wizards did away with the Qilin selection because it was exceedingly difficult to find someone pure of heart enough, but don&amp;rsquo;t worry, there are two people in the crowd that the Qilin finds pure hearted enough&amp;hellip; Then Grindlewald and Dumbledore fight a bit and them fighting breaks their blood pact trinket and there is not even a real attempt to explain it. It is all just MacGuffins and deus ex machina back and forth for three movies, so I guess it is fitting it finishes with one.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It was pretty clear from the start this one was going to be a mess of a plot when the messiness of the plot was explained away as a counter-measure to Grindlewald&amp;rsquo;s future sight. It justified any amount of unexplained surprises and confusing/unexplained decisions. Similar to the second movie, none of these lands and feels meaningful because there is no earned buy-in to any expectations about what is going on. Maybe there could have been some clever way to wrap it up that made for a satisfying romp, but this sure as hell was not it.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Fantastic Beasts: The Crimes of Grindelwald</title><link>https://daveblogs.me/p/fantastic-beasts-the-crimes-of-grindelwald/</link><pubDate>Sat, 23 Nov 2024 22:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://daveblogs.me/p/fantastic-beasts-the-crimes-of-grindelwald/</guid><description>&lt;img src="https://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/en/3/3c/Fantastic_Beasts_-_The_Crimes_of_Grindelwald_Poster.png" alt="Featured image of post Fantastic Beasts: The Crimes of Grindelwald" />&lt;p>I swill start off by saying it took us two nights to get through the movie. After what felt like an eternity the first go around, we realized we still had fifty minutes left and were not confident we were going to be able to stay awake to finish it off (and let&amp;rsquo;s just say the plot was not compelling enough an argument). Starting off with one positive, there are some really great visuals. The costume design is strong and blends allusions to historic styles with witchy elements that is effective. Also, the magic often looks great as well (at least when it looks magical and not just mechanical). However, this is all just visuals, everything below that is confusing and vapid.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>A major problem with the movie is that the cental plot focusing on Credence&amp;rsquo;s origin story is not overly compelling and we are just told through monologues that it is of the upmost importance that he is not united with Grindelwald. In the meantime, the movie burns through characters in service of plot twists that are as confusing as they are unearned. In many cases, the plot twist follows just after we get some clarification about what the heck is actually going on. The result is that it all just feels meaningless, the twist only matters if we felt some clear expectation about what was going to happen, and the movie never gives us that grounding.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>There is also so little of a look into what is really compelling about Grindelwald vision. We have the allusion to World War II that feels slightly compelling in the moment, but does not explained what pulled so many wizards to the meeting in the first place. Credence&amp;rsquo;s pull was very personal and just about his origin. The only other character we get insight into is Queenie, and it is unclear if she was brainwashed or if she really believes in Grindelwald&amp;rsquo;s vision as the only path to happiness with Jacob. But Queenie&amp;rsquo;s story again does little to explain the rest of the mob, as her&amp;rsquo;s is about more free relations between wizards and muggles, and it sure seems like the rest of the mob wants a more clear pecking order and different place for muggles in society.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I am thankful there is only one more movie in the series to call it done&amp;hellip;&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>